Guide to the Mary McCarthy Papers, circa 1915-2013 (bulk 1960-1989)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES VII: LEGAL AND FINANCIAL MATERIAL
  - Lillian Hellman Lawsuit
    - Lawsuit of Lillian Hellman (Folder 370.3)
  - Financial Records
    - Personal business correspondence — Books, newspapers, and magazines, 1970-1988 (Folder 260.1)
    - Personal business correspondence — McCarthy to Chloes's Bookstore, Sacremento, 1979-1982 (Folder 394.15)
    - Personal business correspondence — Domestic help, 1986-1988 (Folder 260.2)
    - Personal business correspondence — Store accounts and shopping, 1970-1988 (Folder 260.3)
    - Personal business correspondence — Travel, 1959-1988 (Folder 260.4)
    - Personal business correspondence — Miscellaneous, 1948, 1958-1964 (Folder 260.5)
    - Personal business correspondence — Miscellaneous, 1971-1988 (Folder 260.6)
    - Bank Accounts — Bank of New York, 1959-1960 (Folder 260.7)
    - Bank Accounts — Bank of New York, 1967-1988 (Folder 260.8)
    - Bank Accounts — Bank of New York, 1981-1990 (Folders 371.1 - 371.2)
    - Bank Accounts — Barclays, 1971-1976 (Folder 260.9)
    - Bank Accounts — Fleet, 1988-1990 (Folder 371.3)
    - Bank Accounts — Lloyds, 1965-1972 (Folder 260.10)
    - Bank Accounts — Lloyds, 1975-1976 (Folder 260.11)
    - Bank Accounts — Lloyds, 1981-1989; (4 folders) (Box 373)
    - Bank Accounts — Merrill, 1974-1977, 1982 (Folder 260.12)
    - Bank Accounts — Merrill, 1981-1988 (Folders 371.4 - 371.6)
    - Bank Accounts — Merrill, 1974-1977, 1982 (Folder 260-12)
    - Bank Accounts — Riggs, 1973-1977 (Folder 260.13)
    - Bank Accounts — Société Générale, 1970-1977 (Folder 260.14)
    - Bank Accounts — State Department Federal Credit Union, 1968-1973 (Folder 260.15)
    - Bank Accounts — cancelled checks, 1954-1989 (Box 263)
    - Bank Accounts — check stubs, 1966-1976 (Box 264)
    - Bank Accounts — cancelled checks and check stubs (Box 372)
    - Insurance (Folder 261.1)
    - Dwellings — Paris apartment — General, 1962-1986 (Folders 261.2 - 261.5)
    - Dwellings — Paris apartment — General, 1970-1989 (Folders 374.1 - 374.4)
    - Dwellings — Paris apartment — Insurance and shipping, 1962-1963 (Folder 261.6)
    - Dwellings — Paris apartment — Furnishings and decor, 1960-1972 (Folders 261.7 - 261.8)
    - Dwellings — Paris apartment — Furnishings and decor, 1973-1989 (Folders 374.5 - 374.6)
    - Dwellings — Paris apartment — Venini lights, 1969 (Folder 374.10)
    - Dwellings — Paris apartment — Utilities, 1970-1972 (Folder 261.9)
    - Dwellings — Paris apartment — Utilities, 1975-1989 (Folders 374.7 - 374.8)
    - Dwellings — Paris apartment — Miscellaneous expenses, 1970-1972 (Folder 261.10)
    - Dwellings — Paris apartment — Miscellaneous (Folder 374.9)
    - Dwellings — Castine house — Furnishings and decor, 1962-1986, undated (Folders 375.1 - 375.4)
    - Dwellings — Castine house — Correspondence with Elmer and Edie Wardwell, 1970-1981 (Folder 375.5)
    - Dwellings — Castine house — Utilities, 1983, 1988-1989 (Folder 375.6)
    - Dwellings — Castine house — Clippings (Folder 375.7)
    - Dwellings — Castine house — Miscellaneous expenses, 1969-1970 (Folder 265.1)
    - Dwellings — Castine house — Miscellaneous expenses, 1974-1988 (Folder 265.2)
    - Dwellings — Castine house — Miscellaneous expenses, 1983 (Folder 375.8)
    - Dwellings — Castine house — Miscellaneous, 1967-1989 (Folder 375.9)
    - Dwellings — Wellfleet house, 1952, 1955 (Folder 265.1)
    - Dwellings — Country houses, 1965-1968 (Folder 375.10)
    - Dwellings — Country houses — Correspondence with Marie-Claire Blais, 1965-1968, undated (Folder 375.11)
    - Dwellings — Florence apartment, 1958 (Folder 375.12)
    - Dwellings — Mortgages, 1990 (Folder 382.1)
    - Social Security, 1981-1989 (Folder 382.2)
    - Taxes — Returns, 1949 (Folder 381.1)
    - Taxes, 1950-1958 (Folder 266.1)
    - Taxes — Returns, 1959-1977 (Folders 266.2 - 266.11)
    - Taxes — Returns, 1981-1990 (Folders 381.2 - 381.4)
    - Taxes — Income, 1959-1976; (12 folders) (Boxes 267-268)
    - Taxes — Income — Royalties and other income, 1980-1983 (Folders 379.1 - 379.2)
    - Taxes — Income — Royalties and other income, 1985-1990 (Folders 380.1 - 380.2)
    - Taxes — Income — Profits from the United Artists movie The Group, 1967-1971; (16 folders) (Box 276)
    - Taxes — Expenses, 1959-1985; (17 folders) (Boxes 269-272)
    - Taxes — Expenses — Books and theater, 1970, 1974 (Folders 273.1 - 273.2)
    - Taxes — Expenses — Books, Newspapers and Magazines, 1981-1989 (Folder 376.1)
    - Taxes — Expenses — Car (Mercedes), 1969-1976 (Folders 273.3 - 273.5)
    - Taxes — Expenses — Castine house, 1970-1976 (Folders 274.1 - 274.5)
    - Taxes — Expenses — Charitable contributions, 1971-1975 (Folder 274.6)
    - Taxes — Expenses — Charitable contributions, 1980-1983 (Folder 376.2)
    - Taxes — Expenses — Charitable contributions, 1986-1989 (Folder 376.3)
    - Taxes — Expenses — Domestic help (Folder 376.4)
    - Taxes — Expenses — Dues, 1982-1989 (Folder 376.5)
    - Taxes — Expenses — Entertainment, 1970-1975 (Folders 274.7 - 274.9)
    - Taxes — Expenses — Entertainment and meals, 1981-1989 (Folder 376.6)
    - Taxes — Expenses — Flowers, 1981-1988 (Folder 376.7)
    - Taxes — Expenses — Grooming, 1981-1989 (Folder 377.1)
    - Taxes — Expenses — Laundry and alterations, 1983-1989 (Folder 377.2)
    - Taxes — Expenses — Medical, 1961-1978 (Folder 275.1)
    - Taxes — Expenses — Secretarial, postage and office, 1981-1989 (Folder 377.3)
    - Taxes — Expenses — Store accounts and shopping, 1968, 1981-1989 (Folder 377.4)
    - Taxes — Expenses — Travel — Vietnam and Cambodia, 1967 (Folder 275.2)
    - Taxes — Expenses — Travel, 1969-1976 (Folders 275.3 - 275.9)
    - Taxes — Expenses — Travel, 1981-1989 (Folders 377.5 - 377.8)
- SERIES VIII: PHOTOGRAPHS
  - Mary McCarthy
    - As infant and child (Folder 277.1)
    - Mary – child (Folder 386.9)
    - Young Mary (Folder 386.12)
    - Annie Wright Seminary (Folder 386.1)
    - Portrait: Annie Wright student. Photographer: Leonid Finch, Seattle, [circa 1928] (Folder 277.2)
    - Portrait: Annie Wright student. Photographer: Leonid Finch, Seattle, [circa 1928] (Folder 277.2)
    - Portrait. Photographer: Henri Jacobs, Tacoma, [1929] (Folder 277.3)
    - At Vassar, 1930-1932 (Folder 277.4)
    - Vassar senior portrait. Photographer: Irving Chidnoff, New York; Joke photo, 1933 (Folder 277.5)
    - Snapshots, [1940s] (Folder 277.6)
    - Portrait. Photographer: Philippe Halsman, New York, 1942 (Folder 277.7)
    - Portrait. Photographer: Gene Fenn, 1944 (Folder 277.8)
    - Portraits. Photographer: Kevin McCarthy, [circa 1949?] (Folder 277.9)
    - Contact sheets. Photographer: Ralph Ellison, 1949 (Folder 277.10)
    - Portraits. Photographer: Ralph Ellison, 1949 (Folder 277.11)
    - Portraits. Photographer: Sylvia Salmi, Wellfleet, MA, [circa summer 1942] (Folder 278.1)
    - Portraits for Cast a Cold Eye, 1950 (Folder 278.2)
    - Portraits. Photographer: [Kevin McCarthy?], [circa 1950?] (Folder 278.3)
    - Portraits taken at Portsmouth, RI. Photographer: [Kevin McCarthy?], [circa 1950?] (Folder 278.4)
    - Portrait for Providence Sunday Journal, [circa 1950] (Folder 278.5)
    - Portrait for Providence Sunday Journal, [circa 1952] (Folder 278.6)
    - Portrait at Westport, CT harbor. Photographer: Kevin O'Flaherty McCarthy, [circa 1952] (Folder 278.7)
    - Portraits. Photographer: Cecil Beaton, London, 1955-1959 (Folder 278.8)
    - Portrait taken at Peggy Guggenheim's. Photographer: Islay Lyons, Rome, [circa 1956] (Folder 278.9)
    - Portrait. Photographer: Inge Mörath-Magnum Photos, 1956 (Folder 278.10)
    - Portrait. Photographer unknown, [circa 1957] (Folder 278.11)
    - Contact prints. Photographer: Richard Avedon, New York, 1959 (Folder 278.12)
    - Contact sheets. Photographer: Cecil Beaton, London, 1959 (Folder 278.13)
    - Informal shots, [1950s] (Folder 278.14)
    - Portrait for The Company She Keeps, 1960 (Folder 279.1)
    - Snapshots in Europe, 1960-1961 (Folder 279.2)
    - Portraits in Berlin. Photographer: Joseph Hunyady, Hungary, 1961 (Folder 279.3)
    - Informal shots for The Group. Photographer: Gisele Freund, Paris, 1962 (Folder 279.4)
    - Photos from The Group (Folder 394.7)
    - Portrait. Photographer: André Morain, Paris, 1963 (Folder 279.5)
    - Portrait. Photographer: Jack Nisberg, London [for Newsweek ], 1963 (Folder 279.6)
    - Portrait in Paris. Unnamed Italian priest, [circa 1964] (Folder 279.7)
    - Informal shots at Jim Jones' home. Photographer: Stanley Marcus, Fall 1965 (Folder 279.8)
    - Informal shots. Photographer: Otto Breicha, Vienna, 1967 (Folder 279.9)
    - Snapshots at office of Dr. Seymour Bonwit. Photographer: Kevin McCarthy, 1969 (Folder 279.10)
    - Portrait. Photographer: Rollie McKenna, Stonington, CT, 1969 (Folder 279.11)
    - Informal shots and snapshots, 1960s (Folder 279.12)
    - Snapshots in Venice. Photographer: Kevin McCarthy, [1960s?] (Folder 279.13)
    - Informal shots for Birds of America. Photographer: Jack Nisberg, [circa 1970] (Folder 279.14)
    - Contact sheets. Photographer: Ray Wilson, 1971 (Folder 279.15)
    - Portraits in Paris. Photographer: Ray Wilson, 1971 (Folder 279.16)
    - Portrait. Photographer: Nancy Crampton, New York, [circa 1973?] (Folder 279.17)
    - Portraits for Minneapolis Journal article. Photographer: Kent Kobersteen, Minneapolis, 1973 (Folder 279.18)
    - Informal shots at Watergate hearings. Photographer: Marc Riboud-Magnum, 1973 (Folder 279.19)
    - Contact sheets. Photographer: Mark Antman, 1976 (Folder 279.20)
    - Informal shots. Photographer: Mark Antman, 1976 (Folder 279.21)
    - Portrait in Paris. Photographer: Cartier-Bresson, [1970s?] (Folder 279.22)
    - Portrait for Le Figaro, [1970s?] (Folder 279.23)
    - Contact sheets. Photographer: Jill Krementz, New York, [1970s?] (Folder 279.24)
    - Portrait. Photographer: Jill Krementz, New York, [1970s?] (Folder 279.25)
    - Portraits. Photographer: Carlos Freire, Paris, 1977-1980 (Folder 280.1)
    - Portraits. Photographer: Rhoda Nathans, New York, [1982?] (Folder 280.2)
    - Informal shots. Photographer: FEREFOTO, London, [1980s] (Folder 280.3)
    - Informal shots. Photographer: Martine Franck/VIVA, Paris, [1980s] (Folder 280.4)
    - Portrait. Photographer: Kelly Wise, [1980s] (Folder 280.5)
    - Informal shots. Photographer: SW, [circa 1980s] (Folder 280.6)
    - Contact sheets. Photographer: Gisele Freund, Paris, undated (Folder 280.7)
    - Informal shots in England, undated (Folder 280.8)
    - Horst Tappe portrait, with accompanying letter from Penny Penwick, [London] Sunday Times (Folder 391.1)
    - In front of balcony – from magazine (Folder 386.3)
    - Mary – assorted – color (Folder 386.4)
    - Mary at desk, 1987, undated (Folder 386.5)
    - Mary at reception (Folder 386.6)
    - Mary – Bard College (Folder 386.7)
    - Mary – Black and white assorted (Folder 386.8)
    - Mary – various (Folder 386.10)
    - Mary wearing hat (Folder 386.17)
    - Passport photos, undated (Folder 280.9)
    - Passport photos (Folder 386.11)
  - Preston and McCarthy Families
    - McCarthy Family, circa 1915 (Folder 386.13)
    - Preston and McCarthy Families (Box 281)
  - Harold Johnsrud and Wilson Family
    - Harold Johnsrud (Folder 386.14)
    - Harold Johnsrud, Edmund Wilson, and Wilson Families (Box 282)
  - Bowden Broadwater and West Family
    - Jim West (Folder 386.15)
    - Mary with Bowden (Folder 386.16)
    - Bowden Broadwater, James West, and West Family (Box 283)
  - Friends and Acquaintances
    - Hanna Arendt (Folder 387.1)
    - Nooteboom and Booth at Castine (Folder 387.2)
    - Friends and acquaintances (Box 284)
  - Residences
    - Residences (Box 285)
  - Places and Events
    - Bard College Commencement, 1989 (Folder 387.3)
    - Bard Luncheon (Folder 387.4)
    - Colby College Honorary Degree Ceremony (Folder 387.5)
    - University of Maine Honorary Degree Ceremony (Folder 387.9)
    - University of Maine Honorary Degree Ceremony (Folder 386.2)
    - Syracuse University Honorary Degree Ceremony, 12 May 1973 (Folder 387.10)
    - Unidentified Honorary Degree Ceremony (Folder 387.6)
    - Mary’s Funeral (Folder 387.7)
    - Mary’s grave (Folder 387.8)
    - Places and events (Box 286-288)
  - Miscellaneous/Unidentified People and Places
    - Unidentified slides (Folder 387.11)
    - Unidentified prints (Folder 387.12)
    - Unidentified negatives (Folder 387.13)
    - Miscellaneous photographs of unidentified people and places (Box 289)
  - Oversized Photographs
    - Mary Smoking (Folder 391.5)
    - "C" Print of How I Grew cover, with accompanying letter (Folder 391.4)
    - Clipping from magazine - picture of Mary leaving for Vassar, 1929 (Folder 391.3)
    - Framed portrait of McCarthy as a child, [1916] (Box 290)
    - Student Body of Annie Wright Seminary, Tacoma Washington, 1929? (Map Case - Drawer 34)
    - Miscellaneous oversized photographs (Box 291)
  - Photograph Albums
    - Photo album of Mary McCarthy (Box 292)
    - Photo album of Roy McCarthy (Box 293)
- SERIES IX: AUDIOVISUAL MEDIA
  - Audiotapes
    - Mary McCarthy, 1953 Nov 11; (4 tapes) (Box 388)
    - Mary McCarthy, 1963 Nov 10; (1 tape) (Box 388)
    - Mary McCarthy, 1969 Oct 26; (1 tape) (Box 388)
    - Mary McCarthy, 1979 Oct 15; (4 tapes) (Box 388)
    - Mary McCarthy, 1982 Sep 21; (1 tape) (Box 388)
    - Mary McCarthy, 1982 Oct 4; (4 tapes) (Box 388)
    - Mary McCarthy, 1987 Sep 21; (2 tapes) (Box 388)
    - Interview with Mary McCarthy, Radioscopie, 1972 Jun 22; (1 tape) (Box 295)
    - Hannah Arendt Recollected, 1980 Mar 14; (1 tape) (Box 295)
    - Interview with Doris Grumbach (Paris), 1966 Jan 19; (1 tape) (Box 295)
    - Mary McCarthy Memorial Service (NY), 1989 Nov 8; (1 tape) (Box 295)
  - Videotapes
    - Moyers-Hellman interview, 1984 Jul 4; (1 tape) (Box 294)
    - BBC broadcast, "Monitor: 46,", 1960 Feb 28; (1 tape) (Box 294)
    - BBC broadcast, "Bookstand,", 1963 Jan 8; (1 tape) (Box 294)
    - BBC broadcast, "Take It or Leave It,", 1964 Dec 13; (1 tape) (Box 294)
    - BBC broadcast, "Tonight Special: No Mean City,", 1965 Mar 28; (1 tape) (Box 294)
    - BBC broadcast, "Personal Choice: Mary McCarthy,", 1968 Jan 14; (1 tape) (Box 294)
- SERIES X. ARTIFACTS and EPHEMERA
  - Awards
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences fellowship, 1974 (Folder 393.6 (Oversize))
    - Tube fore American Academy of Arts and Sciences certificate, 1974 (Box 392)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters - Pegasus Pin, 2 Dec 1988 (Box 392)
    - Annie Wright School Alumnae Central Achievement Award for Literature certificate, May 1984 (Folder 391.7)
    - Confrérie des Chevaliers du Tastevin - awards dinner program (Folder 391.6)
    - Edward MacDowell Award medal, 26 Aug 1984 (Box 392)
    - National Medal for Literature medal, 1984 (Box 392)
    - Stony Brook Foundation Award for Distinguished Contributions to Higher Education certificate, 26 May 1983 (Box 391)
    - Vassar College President’s Distinguished Visitor medal, 1982 (Box 392)
    - Vassar College President’s Distinguished Visitor medal - velvet support, 1982 (Box 391)
  - Honorary Degrees
    - Syracuse University Honorary Degree certificate (Folder 393.5 (Oversize))
    - Tube for Syracuse University Honorary Degree (Box 392)
    - Tulane University Honorary Degree (Folder 391.8)
    - Tube for University of Hull Honorary Degree (Box 392)
    - University of Aberdeen Honorary Degree (Folder 393.8 (Oversize))
  - Miscellaneous
    - "James Raymond West" and "Mr. and Mrs. James Raymond Rest" Business Cards and Plate (Box 392)
    - Reading Glasses (Box 392)
    - "Ernest Medina Trial" Photograph of sketch, signed Preston Russell, (12" x 16.5") (Folder 393.3 (Oversize))
    - "Ernest Medina Trial" Photograph of sketch, signed Preston Russell, (8" x 10") (Folder 393.3 (Oversize))
    - "The Group" Advertisement poster for book, 1966 (Map Case - Drawer 33)
    - Swedish Female Writers Poster, 1981; (2 copies) (Map Case - Drawer 33)
    - "Mary McCarthy: A Tribute" Vassar College Poster, 1990; (3 copies) (Map Case - Drawer 37)
    - "The Poets' Theatre Proudly Presents An Evening with Mary McCarthy,", undated (Map Case - Drawer 37)
    - List of contributors to the Peggy Guggenheim Collection, 1981 (Map Case - Drawer 37)
- SERIES XI. UNPROCESSED MATERIAL
  - M2019-046, [clippings] (Box 395.1)
  - M2020-010, [correspondence, photographs] (Box 395.2)
  - Unaccessioned ephemera (Box 395.3)